export default {
  id: 'grammar_word_2_1',
  name: '문법책 단어 (2-1 / 200자 / 뜻)',
  data: [
    { question: '広い', answer: ['ひろい', '넓다'] },
    { question: '部屋', answer: ['へや', '방'] },
    { question: '狭い', answer: ['せまい', '좁다'] },
    { question: '傘', answer: ['かさ', '우산'] },
    { question: '高い', answer: ['たかい', '높다, 비싸다'] },
    { question: 'スカーフ', answer: ['', '스카프'] },
    { question: '安い', answer: ['やすい', '싸다'] },
    { question: '富士山', answer: ['ふじさん', '후지산'] },
    { question: '低い', answer: ['ひくい', '낮다'] },
    { question: '椅子', answer: ['いす', '의자'] },
    { question: '机', answer: ['つくえ', '책상'] },
    { question: '絵', answer: ['え', '그림'] },
    { question: '音楽', answer: ['おんがく', '음악'] },
    { question: '大きな', answer: ['おおきな', '큰 (예외 い형용사)'] },
    { question: '小さな', answer: ['ちいさな', '작은 (예외 い형용사)'] },
    { question: '小説', answer: ['しょうせつ', '소설'] },
    { question: '面白い', answer: ['おもしろい', '재미있다'] },
    { question: '冗談', answer: ['じょうだん', '농담'] },
    { question: '詰まらない', answer: ['つまらない', '재미없다'] },
    { question: '選手', answer: ['せんしゅ', '선수'] },
    { question: '強い', answer: ['つよい', '강하다'] },
    { question: 'チーム', answer: ['', '팀'] },
    { question: '弱い', answer: ['よわい', '약하다'] },
    { question: '今月', answer: ['こんげつ', '이번 달'] },
    { question: '忙しい', answer: ['いそがしい', '바쁘다'] },
    { question: '人生', answer: ['じんせい', '인생'] },
    { question: '長い', answer: ['ながい', '길다'] },
    { question: '夏休み', answer: ['なつやすみ', '여름방학'] },
    { question: '短い', answer: ['みじかい', '짧다'] },
    { question: '兄', answer: ['あに', '형, 오빠'] },
    { question: '腕', answer: ['うで', '팔'] },
    { question: '太い', answer: ['ふとい', '굵다'] },
    { question: '足', answer: ['あし', '다리'] },
    { question: '細い', answer: ['ほそい', '가늘다'] },
    { question: '若い', answer: ['わかい', '젊다'] },
    { question: 'ピッチャー', answer: ['', '투수, 피처'] },
    { question: 'ストレート', answer: ['', '스트레이트, 직구'] },
    { question: '速い', answer: ['はやい', '(속도가) 빠르다'] },
    { question: '早い', answer: ['はやい', '(시간, 시기가) 빠르다, 이르다'] },
    { question: 'インターネット', answer: ['', '인터넷'] },
    { question: 'スピード', answer: ['', '스피드'] },
    { question: '遅い', answer: ['おそい', '느리다'] },
    { question: '海外旅行', answer: ['かいがいりょこう', '해외여행'] },
    { question: '楽しい', answer: ['たのしい', '즐겁다'] },
    { question: '注射', answer: ['ちゅうしゃ', '주사'] },
    { question: '痛い', answer: ['いたい', '(통증으로) 아프다'] },
    { question: '犬', answer: ['いぬ', '개'] },
    { question: '可愛い', answer: ['かわいい', '귀엽다, 예쁘다'] },
    { question: 'ケーキ', answer: ['', '케이크'] },
    { question: '甘い', answer: ['あまい', '달다'] },
    { question: '辛い', answer: ['からい', '맵다'] },
    { question: '祖母', answer: ['そぼ', '할머니'] },
    { question: 'カレー', answer: ['', '카레'] },
    { question: '美味しい', answer: ['おいしい', '맛있다'] },
    { question: '晩御飯', answer: ['ばんごはん', '저녁밥'] },
    { question: '不味い', answer: ['まずい', '맛없다'] },
    { question: '味', answer: ['あじ', '맛'] },
    { question: '悪い', answer: ['わるい', '나쁘다'] },
    { question: '見る', answer: ['みる', '보다'] },
    { question: '朝御飯', answer: ['あさごはん', '아침밥'] },
    { question: '食べる', answer: ['たべる', '먹다'] },
    { question: '着物', answer: ['きもの', '옷, 일본옷'] },
    { question: '和服', answer: ['わふく', '일본옷'] },
    { question: '着る', answer: ['きる', '입다'] },
    { question: '窓', answer: ['まど', '창문'] },
    { question: '開ける', answer: ['あける', '열다'] },
    { question: '閉める', answer: ['しめる', '닫다'] },
    { question: '借りる', answer: ['かりる', '빌리다'] },
    { question: '電気', answer: ['でんき', '전기, 불'] },
    { question: '付ける', answer: ['つける', '켜다, 붙이다'] },
    { question: '電話', answer: ['でんわ', '전화'] },
    { question: '掛ける', answer: ['かける', '걸다, (안경을) 쓰다'] },
    { question: '答え', answer: ['こたえ', '대답, 해답'] },
    { question: '見せる', answer: ['みせる', '보여주다'] },
    { question: '締める', answer: ['しめる', '매다, 조이다'] },
    { question: 'シャワー', answer: ['', '샤워'] },
    { question: '浴びる', answer: ['あびる', '끼얹다, 쬐다, 뒤집어쓰다'] },
    { question: '覚える', answer: ['おぼえる', '외우다, 기억하다'] },
    { question: '教える', answer: ['おしえる', '가르치다'] },
    { question: '名前', answer: ['なまえ', '이름'] },
    { question: '電話番号', answer: ['でんわばんごう', '전화번호'] },
    { question: '忘れる', answer: ['わすれる', '잊어버리다'] },
    { question: 'お皿', answer: ['おさら', '접시'] },
    { question: '並べる', answer: ['ならべる', '늘어놓다, 나란히 놓다'] },
    { question: '塩', answer: ['しお', '소금'] },
    { question: '入れる', answer: ['いれる', '넣다'] },
    { question: 'アドレス', answer: ['', '어드레스, 주소'] },
    { question: '変える', answer: ['かえる', '바꾸다'] },
    { question: '塵', answer: ['ごみ', '쓰레기'] },
    { question: '捨てる', answer: ['すてる', '버리다'] },
    { question: 'ドイツ語', answer: ['ドイツご', '독일어'] },
    { question: '始める', answer: ['はじめる', '시작하다'] },
    { question: '集める', answer: ['あつめる', '모으다'] },
    { question: '飛行機', answer: ['ひこうき', '비행기'] },
    { question: '調べる', answer: ['しらべる', '알아보다, 조사하다'] },
    { question: '植える', answer: ['うえる', '심다'] },
    { question: '建てる', answer: ['たてる', '짓다'] },
    { question: '漬ける', answer: ['つける', '담다'] },
    { question: '眼鏡', answer: ['めがね', '안경'] },
    { question: '値段', answer: ['ねだん', '값, 가격'] },
    { question: '上げる', answer: ['あげる', '올리다'] },
    { question: 'コスト', answer: ['', '코스트, 비용'] },
    { question: '下げる', answer: ['さげる', '내리다'] },
    { question: '辞める', answer: ['やめる', '그만두다'] },
    { question: '片付ける', answer: ['かたづける', '치우다'] },
    { question: 'クラスメート', answer: ['', '클래스메이트'] },
    { question: '苛める', answer: ['いじめる', '괴롭히다'] },
    { question: '昔', answer: ['むかし', '옛날'] },
    { question: '日記', answer: ['にっき', '일기'] },
    { question: '見付ける', answer: ['みつける', '발견하다, 찾아내다'] },
    { question: '電球', answer: ['でんきゅう', '전구'] },
    { question: '取り替える', answer: ['とりかえる', '갈다, 교체하다'] },
    { question: '結婚', answer: ['けっこん', '결혼'] },
    { question: '決める', answer: ['きめる', '결정하다'] },
    { question: '泥棒', answer: ['どろぼう', '도둑'] },
    { question: '捕まえる', answer: ['つかまえる', '잡다'] },
    { question: '忘れ物', answer: ['わすれもの', '분실물'] },
    { question: '届ける', answer: ['とどける', '갖다 주다'] },
    { question: '運動', answer: ['うんどう', '운동'] },
    { question: '続ける', answer: ['つづける', '계속하다'] },
    { question: '受ける', answer: ['うける', '받다, (시험을) 보다'] },
    { question: '試験を受ける', answer: ['しけんをうける', '시험을 보다'] },
    { question: '褒める', answer: ['ほめる', '칭찬하다'] },
    { question: '止める', answer: ['とめる', '세우다'] },
    { question: '停める', answer: ['とめる', '(차를) 세우다'] },
    { question: '道', answer: ['みち', '길'] },
    { question: '間違える', answer: ['まちがえる', '틀리다, 잘못하다, 잘못 알다'] },
    { question: '書く', answer: ['かく', '쓰다, 전산에 기록하다'] },
    { question: 'お茶', answer: ['おちゃ', '차'] },
    { question: '飲む', answer: ['のむ', '마시다'] },
    { question: '鉛筆', answer: ['えんぴつ', '연필'] },
    { question: '送る', answer: ['おくる', '보내다'] },
    { question: '火', answer: ['ひ', '불'] },
    { question: '消す', answer: ['けす', '끄다'] },
    { question: '知る', answer: ['しる', '알다'] },
    { question: 'たばこ', answer: ['', '담배'] },
    { question: '吸う', answer: ['すう', '흡입하다, 피우다'] },
    { question: '脱ぎる', answer: ['ぬぎる', '벗다'] },
    { question: '新聞', answer: ['しんぶん', '신문'] },
    { question: '読む', answer: ['よむ', '읽다'] },
    { question: '写真', answer: ['しゃしん', '사진'] },
    { question: '撮る', answer: ['とる', '찍다, 촬영하다'] },
    { question: '雑誌', answer: ['ざっし', '잡지'] },
    { question: '貸す', answer: ['かす', '빌려주다'] },
    { question: '待つ', answer: ['まつ', '기다리다'] },
    { question: '習う', answer: ['ならう', '배우다'] },
    { question: 'お金', answer: ['おかね', '돈'] },
    { question: '返る', answer: ['かえる', '돌려주다'] },
    { question: '呼ぶ', answer: ['よぶ', '부르다'] },
    { question: '歯', answer: ['は', '이, 치아'] },
    { question: '磨く', answer: ['みがく', '닦다'] },
    { question: '財布', answer: ['さいふ', '지갑'] },
    { question: '無くす', answer: ['なくす', '잃어버리다, 분실하다'] },
    { question: '薬', answer: ['くすり', '약'] },
    { question: '授業', answer: ['じゅぎょう', '수업'] },
    { question: '靴下', answer: ['くつした', '양말'] },
    { question: '説明書', answer: ['せつめいしょ', '설명서'] },
    { question: '恋人', answer: ['こいびと', '연인'] },
    { question: '喜ぶ', answer: ['よろこぶ', '기뻐하다'] },
    { question: 'クラシック', answer: ['', '클래식'] },
    { question: 'ズボン', answer: ['', '바지'] },
    { question: '弾く', answer: ['ひく', '연주하다'] },
    { question: '履く', answer: ['はく', '신다'] },
    { question: 'におい', answer: ['', '냄새'] },
    { question: '嗅ぐ', answer: ['かぐ', '(냄새를) 맡다'] },
    { question: '花瓶', answer: ['かびん', '화병'] },
    { question: '葉書', answer: ['はがき', '엽서'] },
    { question: '持つ', answer: ['もつ', '들다, 가지다'] },
    { question: '洗う', answer: ['あらう', '씻다'] },
    { question: '売る', answer: ['うる', '팔다'] },
    { question: '掃除', answer: ['そうじ', '청소'] },
    { question: '頼む', answer: ['たのむ', '부탁하다, 의뢰하다'] },
    { question: '踏む', answer: ['ふむ', '밟다'] },
    { question: '選ぶ', answer: ['えらぶ', '고르다, 선택하다'] },
    { question: '万年筆', answer: ['まんねんひつ', '만년필'] },
    { question: '押す', answer: ['おす', '누르다, 밀다'] },
    { question: '差す', answer: ['さす', '가리다, (우산을) 쓰다'] },
    { question: '自動車', answer: ['じどうしゃ', '자동차'] },
    { question: '楽しむ', answer: ['たのしむ', '즐기다, 기대하다'] },
    { question: '興味', answer: ['きょうみ', '흥미, 관심'] },
    { question: 'ヨーロッパ', answer: ['', '유럽'] },
    { question: 'ガソリンスタンド', answer: ['', '주유소'] },
    { question: 'お手洗い', answer: ['おてあらい', '화장실'] },
    { question: '明後日', answer: ['あさって', '모레'] },
    { question: '課長', answer: ['かちょう', '과장'] },
    { question: '講義', answer: ['こうぎ', '강의'] },
    { question: '準備', answer: ['じゅんび', '준비'] },
    { question: '競争', answer: ['きょうそう', '경쟁'] },
    { question: 'いとこ', answer: ['', '사촌'] },
    { question: '返事', answer: ['へんじ', '대답, 답장'] },
    { question: '喧嘩', answer: ['けんか', '싸움'] },
    { question: '洗濯', answer: ['せんたく', '세탁'] },
    { question: '社会科学', answer: ['しゃかいかがく', '사회과학'] },
    { question: '研究', answer: ['けんきゅう', '연구'] },
    { question: '案内', answer: ['あんない', '안내'] },
    { question: '散歩', answer: ['さんぽ', '산보'] },
    { question: '質問', answer: ['しつもん', '질문'] },
    { question: '花火', answer: ['はなび', '불꽃놀이'] },
    { question: '見物', answer: ['けんぶつ', '구경, 구경꾼'] },
    { question: '下宿', answer: ['げしゅく', '하숙'] }
  ]
}
